<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smriti Suresh</title>
    <link>https://smritae01.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Smriti Suresh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 12:01:24 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smritae01.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Political Speech Generation and Analysis</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/pol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/pol/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Project concerned with generating political speech coherent with the styles of renowned world leaders through Deep Learning models and Large Language models and assessing their accuracy in producing new content that keeps in line with the vocabulary, style and tone of the political figure chosen. Data science is used to create visualizations on the generated text comparing it to the original text. Here&amp;rsquo;s a funny meme from the Orange County Register that is in line with what the project tries to assess!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbaria OCR</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ocr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ocr/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Project concerned with Herbaria OCR techniques to extract all text from a given image to display the specimen information in the desired DarwinCore format for accomplishing the larger goal of preservation of early 19th century species through digitization. Machine learning pipeline using AI Vision models as well as text processing through GPT-4 along with evaluation of the training data was done successfully, culminating in deployment and a poster presentation to the BU Spark!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grace Hopper Conference 2023</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ghc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ghc/</guid>
      <description>🎇👩‍💻My GHC experience!!👩‍💻🎇 🌟 I was thrilled to be a part of the Boston University cohort for GHC attendees in person this year and the conference lived upto its name indeed! Surrounded by empowering and intelligent women and non-binary folk in Tech really gave me a new surge of energy and determination in making the most out of GHC this year. The career fair and expo of GHC was the main highlight of the conference for me, as the sheer scale of it was enough to intimidate anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting Patterns in Boston</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ds4g/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ds4g/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Project concerned with using Data Analysis and Data Science to assess Voting Patterns among minority communities within Boston, using data provided by the office of City of Boston Councillor Julia Mejia. Interactive maps and results available here!
Motivation This project undertaken by the initiative of City Councillor Julia Mejia was concerned with voting patterns in the Latine/Latinx community amongst different communities of eligible voters, registered voters, voter turnout, precinct breakdown, demographic information (age and gender breakdown) and many such factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Originality Score Project</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/og/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/og/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Project concerned with creating an evaluation metric for assessing originality of texts produced by AI models, human written texts or a combination of both. The pipeline follows sample data being classified in various ways as AI-written or Human-written by different detector models and combining their scores as per calculated weights to obtain insights into whether the text was truly &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo;.
Motivation The advent of Large Language Models and Neural Networks to generate human-like texts and responses has made a lasting impact on how AI will play a considerable role in automating several corporate and academic environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The COVID-19 Humor Project</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/nlp/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR My first research publication! Project concerned with COVID-19 pandemic humor dataset creation as well as Humor detection and Maladaptive Humor Detection tasks evaluated on state-of-the-art LLM models to assess the subtle and dark nature of pandemic related humor that may serve toward social and mental analysis of a population living through such an era. Here&amp;rsquo;s a high-level pipeline of the project and its steps, check out the Resources for more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MEB Project</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/meb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/meb/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Project concerned with the analysis of mental health surveys of young teens as well as their faculty in building connections and social relationships as part of collective belonging through Data processing, analysis and visualizations. The project culminated successfully with a poster presentation to the clients as well as the BU Spark! Committee. Here are a few visualizations we obtained, for more info check out the resources down below:
Motivation This project seeks to understand the relationship between mental, emotional, and behavioral (MEB) health and the stable experience of belonging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lego Voice Assistant</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/lego/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/lego/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Conversational App Integration with the Core Product Using Technology. This was the topic statement we had to come up with a fully functioning website for that satisified the core objectives of the 2 day long hackathon.
Our train of thought! Approach Our aim was to code a voice assistant that accepts a voice input, and outputs the required result after searching the vast Dell Digital database. To facilitate speech recognition and synthesis, we used the HTML5 Speech Recognition API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m Smriti Suresh, a 23 year old aspiring Data Scientist, and I am ecstatic to share that I very recently successfully obtained my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science at Boston University. I am passionate about Natural Language Processing and all things data. After obtaining my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering from Mahindra Ecole Centrale (now Mahindra University) in Hyderabad, India, I knew I wanted to delve into the intricacies of how natural language and computing combine to produce mind-boggling results (GenAI is insane right now :o).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: smritis [at] bu [dot] edu
LinkedIn | Github | Curriculum Vitae</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
