<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analytics on Smriti Suresh</title>
    <link>https://smritae01.github.io/tags/data-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analytics on Smriti Suresh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 12:01:24 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smritae01.github.io/tags/data-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Voting Patterns in Boston</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ds4g/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/ds4g/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Project concerned with using Data Analysis and Data Science to assess Voting Patterns among minority communities within Boston, using data provided by the office of City of Boston Councillor Julia Mejia. Interactive maps and results available here!
Motivation This project undertaken by the initiative of City Councillor Julia Mejia was concerned with voting patterns in the Latine/Latinx community amongst different communities of eligible voters, registered voters, voter turnout, precinct breakdown, demographic information (age and gender breakdown) and many such factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MEB Project</title>
      <link>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/meb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smritae01.github.io/projects/meb/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Project concerned with the analysis of mental health surveys of young teens as well as their faculty in building connections and social relationships as part of collective belonging through Data processing, analysis and visualizations. The project culminated successfully with a poster presentation to the clients as well as the BU Spark! Committee. Here are a few visualizations we obtained, for more info check out the resources down below:
Motivation This project seeks to understand the relationship between mental, emotional, and behavioral (MEB) health and the stable experience of belonging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
